### **Stephen Thompson**

2453 N Washtenaw Ave Chicago, IL 60647 s31@umbc.edu

#### About me

I am a full-stack web developer living in Chicago, and currently completing the coding boot camp at Northwestern University. I also have a background in applied mathematics, with a particular focus in spatial epidemiology, mathematical economics and differential equations. I love working with the back end of web applications and am excited to apply my coding skills, together with my background in mathematics, in the private sector after several years of teaching. For fun, I like to go on bike rides with my wife Kate.

### Education

Certificate in Full-Stack Web Development, Northwestern University, expected completion December 2021

Doctor of Philosophy, Applied Mathematics University of Maryland, Baltimore County (UMBC), 2013

Master of Science, Applied Mathematics University of Maryland, Baltimore County, 2009

Bachelor of Arts, Mathematics University of Maryland, Baltimore County, 2008

## Professional Experience

Part-time instructor
University of Maryland, Baltimore County

1000 Hilltop Circle Baltimore, MD 21250

Courses taught: partial differential equations (Math 404 four times), linear algebra (Math 221, seven times), differential equations (Math 225, three times), multivariable calculus (Math 251, three times) and geometry (Math 306). Also worked as an academic advisor for new students.

High School Teacher
Baltimore City Public Schools
200 E. North Ave
Baltimore, MD 21210

Courses taught: Algebra II and College Readiness Mathematics.

Affiliate Faculty
Loyola University, Maryland
4501 N. Charles St.

2017-2019

2019-2020

2015-2021

Baltimore, MD 21210

Courses taught: Applied Calculus (MA151, once), Calculus I (MA251, twice), Calculus II (MA252, three times).

Collective member
Alternative Press Center
2239 Kirk Ave.
Baltimore, MD 21218

2017-2019

I helped write and edit the Alternative Press Index, which is carried by many academic libraries and is published twice per year.

Part-time instructor
Community College of Baltimore County
10300 Grand Central Ave
Owings Mills, MD 21117

2014-2016

Courses taught: statistics (Math 153, two times), college algebra (Math 163, three times), and high school algebra (Math 081, 082 and 083).

Teaching Assistant

2008-2013

University of Maryland, Baltimore County

Courses taught: calculus I (Math 151), calculus II (Math 152), and precalculus (Math 150).

# Selected publications

Thompson, S. 2020. "Growth, external markets and stock-flow norms: a Luxemburg-Godley model of accumulation." *Cambridge Journal of Economics* 44(2): 417-443.

Thompson, S.: 2014. "Convergence of nonlocal diffusion models on lattices." *Journal of Mathematical Analysis and Applications* 415: 1-13.

Thompson, S. 2013. *Anomalous Diffusion in Subsets of Euclidean Space.* Doctoral dissertation. University of Maryland, Baltimore County.

Thompson, S. and Seidman, T. I. 2013. "Approximation of a Semigroup Model of Anomalous Diffusion in a Bounded Set." *Evolution Equations and Control Theory* 2: 173-192.

Thompson, S. 2010. "An Extension of Browder's Non-Ejective Fixed Point Theorem," *Fixed Point Theory* 11: 143-146.

Service

Volunteer Tutor

2013

Goucher Prison Education Partnership

I tutored students at the mens' prison in Jessup, Maryland.

Member, Fair Labor Standards Advisory Group University of Maryland, Baltimore County

2009

This group reviewed labor issues at factories that produce UMBC's university-logo apparel. The group was appointed by the university president. As a member, I helped convince the administration to affiliate with the Worker Rights Consortium.

Award

Recognized for outstanding mathematics research in 2012 by the College of Natural and Mathematical Sciences, UMBC.

References

Available upon request.